Finding Aid for the The Sigaux Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Farceurs. Handwritten manuscript and notes (mostly about Gaultier Garguille and theatre of the late 1500s and early 1600s). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Georges Feydeau. Typed manuscript ( Les Génies du Théâtre Français - Tome 40: "Feu La Mère de Madame" de Georges Feydeau). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Robert de Flers et G. A. de Caillavet (Robert de Flers and Gaston Arman de Caillavet). Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article/preface, Génies du théâtre français, Tome 40: Le Roi), typed manuscripts (articles: 1 draft of Robert de Fleurs et Gaston Arman de Caillavet, and 1 draft of Le Roi). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Pierre Fresnay. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Pierre Fresnay). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Abel Gance.Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Albert Gance). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Paul Géraldy. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Paul Géraldy). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Paul Ginisty. Typed manuscript (a G. S. article/preface). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Gondinet (Edmond Gondinet). Typed manuscript (a G. S. article, Les Génies du Théâtre Français: Edmond Gondinet, le Panache). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- G. S. sur Sacha Guitry (Sacha Guitry, Lucien Guitry). Typed biograpies (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Guitry (Sacha), 1 draft each: Guitry, Lucien,Guitry, Sacha), typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of,Lucien Guitry, 1860-1925), journal excerpts, typed and handwritten manuscript (Sacha Guitry), G. S. notes, typed manuscript (Histoires que racontait Sacha Guitry), typed manuscript (Guitry (Lucien)). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Alfred Jarry. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of an article/preface, Les Genies du Théâtre Français, Tome 38: Ubu Roi), typed manuscript (an article, Ubu Roi), press clipping. (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Lambert-Thiboust (Pierre-Antoine-Auguste Thiboust). Typed manuscripts (3 drafts of a "notice", Génies du Théâtre Français, Tome 30: Lambert-Thiboust, Un Mari dans du Coton). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Théodore Leclercq (Michel-Théodore Leclercq). Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. "notice", Les Génies du Théâtre Français - Tome 22. Thédore Leclercq: Tous les Comédiens ne sont pas au théâtre). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- H. R. Lenormand (Henri-René Lenormand). Press clipping. (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Claude Magnier. Typed manuscript (an article/preface, Claude Magnier). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Vladimir Vladimirovitch Maïkovski. Typed manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. preface, Théâtre de Maïakovski: Préface). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Meilhac et Halévy (Henry Meilhac and Ludovic Halévy. Journal excerpt, typed manuscripts (articles: Meilhac and Halévy, and Le Reveillon). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Georges Méliès. Typed transcript (a G. S. article for Preuves Informations), press clipping. (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Mirbeau (Octave Mirbeau). Typed manuscript (a G. S. article, Les Génies du Théâtre Français, Tome 40: Les Affaires Sont les Affaires). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Molière (Jean Baptiste Poquelin, known as Molière). Journal excerpts (off-prints of G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles: 4 drafts of Notes pour une Discographie de Molière; 3 drafts of Notes pour une filmographie de Molière; and 4 drafts of Geroges Monval et "Le Moliériste), music catalog pages, G. S. notes. (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Molière T. V. Typed plans (3 drafts for a television show about Molière to be presented by Marie-Ange Horlaville and Gilbert Sigaux). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Gaby Morlay. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Gaby Morlay). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Marcel Pagnol. Typed manuscript (an incomplete draft), journal excerpt (includes a G. S. article), typed manuscripts (2 drafts of an article, Marcel Pagnol, Né en 1895), handwritten manuscript (an article, Marcel Pagnol), typed manuscript (a G. S. article, Un Autre Pagnol). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Pailleron (Edouard Pailleron). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of an article, Les Génies du Théâtre Français, Tome 38: Le Monde où l'on s'ennuie). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Picard (Louis Benoit Picard). Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a "notice", Les Génies du Théâtre Français - Tome 30 - Picard: La Petite Ville). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Erwin Piscator. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Porto Riche. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of an article, Les Génies du Théâtre Français, Tome 38: La Chance de Françoise). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Jan Potocki. Journal excerpt (off-print of a G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Yvonne Printemps. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Yvonne Printemps. (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Regnard (Jean Francois Regnard). Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed manuscript (Notice sur le Joueur et les Folies Amoureuses). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Jules Renard. Typed manuscripts (a G. S. "postface", Postface a trois oeuvres de Jules Renard; an article, Jules Renard 1864-1910; and a G. S. article/preface, Les Génies du Théâtre Français, Tome 39: Le Pain de Ménage). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Romain Rolland. Typed manuscript (a 42 page G. S. article, Romain Rolland. O. C. Théâtre. Tome 18). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Edmond Rostand. Typed manuscript (a G. S. article, Les Génies du Théâtre Français, Tome 39: Cyrano de Bergerac). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- André Roussin.Typed and handwritten manuscript (Andre Roussin- né en 1911), journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Armand Salacrou. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), handwritten manuscript (Armand Salacrou). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Sardou (Victorien Sardou). Typed manuscripts ( 2 drafts of a G. S. article Les Génies du Théâtre Français, Tome 36 - Victorien Sardou: Pattes de Mouche). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Marc-Gilbert Sauvajon. Typed manuscripts (3 drafts of an article, Marc-Gilbert Sauvajon né en 1909). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Scribe (Eugène Scribe). Typed manuscripts (3 drafts of a "notice", La Comédie dans la première moitié du XIXieme siècle. Scribe: L'Ours et le Pacha). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Shakespeare (William Shakespeare). Press clippings (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- G. B. Shaw (George Bernard Shaw). Press clippings (including a G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Michel Simon. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Michel Simon). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Strindberg (August Strindberg). G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Tchekhov (Anton Tchekhov). Typed manuscript (a G. S. forward, Les Livres Qui Ont Fait Le Monde - Tchekhov. Avant-Propos de l'Éditeur). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Claude Vermorel. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Oscar Wilde. Handwritten manuscript (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Émile Zola. Empty. (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Alain (Émile Chartier, known as Alain). Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed manuscript (G. S. article, Notre Ami Alain), press clippings (G. S. articles), typed manuscript (Avec Alain), G. S. notes. (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Marcel Allain. Book excerpts (2 copies of the G. S. preface for Pierre Souvestre and M. Allain's Fantomas), journal excerpts. (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Alphonse Allais. Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of an article, Alphonse Allais 1854-1905). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Ivo Andritch. Journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Aragon (Louis Aragon). Journal excerpt (G. S. article), G. S. notes. (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Marcel Arland. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Marcel Arland). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Georges Arnaud (Henri Girard, known as Georges Arnaud). Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Georges Arnaud (Henri Giraud), Romancier), press clippings. (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Raymond Aron. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), typed manuscript (G. S. article), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Robert Aron. Typed manuscript (article, Aron (Robert)). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Yvan Audouard. Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, Les chefs-d'oeuvre du roman policier. Antoine le Vertueux: Preface). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Marguerite Audoux. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Saint Augustin. Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. forward, Les Livres Qui Ont Fait Le Monde. Saint Augustin: Les Confessions. Avant-Propos de l'Éditeur). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Marcel Aymé. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Marcel Aymé, 1 draft of a brief biography and bibliography). (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Claude Bernard. Handwritten manuscript (a G. S. forward), typed manuscript (Bernard Claude). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Bernard Barbey. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Maurice Barrès. Press clippings, journal excerpts (includes a G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Michel-Aimé Baudouy. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Gérard Bauër. Typed manuscript (a G. S. article, Gérard Bauër). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Vicky Baum. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Sylvia Beach. Press clipping (G. S. article), typed manuscript (a G. S. article/preface, A Livre Ouvert: Shakespeare and Company). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Pierre Béarn. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Simone de Beauvoir. Typed manuscript, press clippings (includes G. S. articles), journal excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Beecher Stowe (Harriet Beecher Stowe). Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface/forward, La Case de l'Oncle Tom: Préface/Avant-Propos). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Julien Benda. Journal excerpt, typed manuscript(Julien Benda). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Georges Bernanos. Handwritten and typed manuscripts (G. S. articles and prefaces: 3 drafts of La vie et l'oeuvre de Georges Bernanos, 1888-1948; and 2 drafts of préface), press clipping (G. S. article), journal excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 61, Folder 7)
- André Billy. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. preface, Préface pour "l'Allegretto de la Septième": André Billy). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Antoine Blondin. Press clipping (G. S. article), handwritten notes (about Marcel Aymé, not in G. S.'s hand). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Léon Blum. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Yves Bonnefoy. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Henry Bordeaux. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Pierre Boulle. Handwritten and typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Pierre Boulle, Romancier). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Emmanuel Bove. Press clipping, book excerpt (G. S. preface), hanwritten manuscript (a G. S. preface, Préface à "Journal écrit en hiver"). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Elizabeth Bowen. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- René Boylesve. Handwritten and typed manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. preface, L'Enfant à la Balustrade), journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Charlotte Brontë. Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, La Vie de Charlotte Brontë, includes typed instructions from G. S., "Note pour la Fabrication"). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Edmond Buchet. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Pearl Buck. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Georges Buraud. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 8)
- José Cabanis. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, José Cabanis: Romancier et Critique). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Roger Caillois. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- James Cain. Press clippings (G. S. articles), typed manuscript (La Technique et la Naïevité: James Cain). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Erskine Caldwell. Press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Taylor Caldwell (Mrs. Taylor Caldwell). Press clipping. (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Albert Camus. G. S. notes, typed manuscripts (G. S. articles: Albert Camus, Itinéraire d'Albert Camus, La Chute), handwritten manuscript (G. S. article: Au Milieu du Chemin...), journal excerpts (includes G. S. articles), press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Joyce Cary. Press clippings (G. S. articles), handwritten manuscript (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Jean Cassou. Handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, Préface à La Clef des Songes), press clipping,s (includes a G. S. article), typed manuscript (a G. S. article, Jean Cassou). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Henry Castillou. Press clipping. (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Willa Cather. Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Dame Perdue (Une) - Roman de Willa Cather (1873-1947...). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Jean Cayrol. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Jean Cayrol, Poète et Romancier). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Céline (Louis-Ferdinand Destouches). Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Cellini (Benvenuto Cellini). Typed manuscript (a G. S. forward, Cellini: Avant-Propos). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Blaise Cendrars. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), handwritten manuscript (a G. S. article, Érivains d'Aujourd'hui: Blaise Cendrars). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- César (Jules César / Caius Julius Caesar). Typed manuscript (a G. S. article, César: La Guerre des Gaules). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Gilbert Cesbron. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Gilbert Cesbron: Romancier). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- J. P. Chabrol (Jean-Pierre Chabrol). Typed manuscript and instructions (a G. S. article, Contes d'outre-temps. P. I. 14-9-69), press clipping (G. S. article), handwritten manuscript. (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Marc Chadourne. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Houston-Stewart Chamberlain. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- André Chamson. Journal excerpts (4 copies of a G. S. article), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Jacques Chardonne. Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, Préface à "L'Épithalame"). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- James Hadley Chase. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Loose Item. A typed manuscript of a preface written by G. S. under the name of Blaise Cendrars (with Cendrars accord). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Chenard 1956 (Christian Chenard). Periodical (Bulletin de la Galerie Raymond Creuze, IV, includes a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Peter Cheyney. Press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- E M Cioran (E.-M. Cioran). Press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- JP Clébert (Jean-Paul Clébert). Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Jean Cocteau. Typed manuscripts (l'Elisabeth des Enfants Terribles, Radio Nationale Mai 1950, Jean Cocteau), press clipping. (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Louis Codet. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (4 drafts of a G. S. preface, La Petite Chiquette). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Colette (Sidonie Gabrielle Colette). Journal excerpts (4 copies of a G. S. article), handwritten and typed manuscripts (G. S. articles/prefaces: 3 drafts of La Naissance du Jour; and 3 drafts of La Retraite Sentimentale). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Ivy Compton-Burnette. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Auguste Comte. Typed manuscript (Auguste Comte, 1798-1857). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Conrad (Joseph Conrad). Journal excerpt (includes G. S. articles), press clipping (G. S. article), typed manuscripts (G. S. articles: Conrad en France; Conrad et le Théâtre, Note bibliographique). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- J. P. Crespelle. Press clipping (G. S. article), typed manuscript (G. S. article Monparnasse: Fantomes et Vivants). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- A. J. Cronin. Press clippings, typed manuscript (A. J. Cronin Docteur en Medecine de l'Université de Glasgow est aussi l'auteur de dix "best-sellers"). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- J. L. Curtis (Jean-Louis Curtis). Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Daniel-Rops. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Pierre Daninos. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), typed biography and bibliography (2 drafts, Pierre Daninos: Notice bio-bibliographique), handwritten manuscript (G. S. preface), G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscript (Pierre Daninos, Romancier). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Dard (Frédéric Dard). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles and prefaces: 2 drafts of an article, Mon Ami Frédéric Dard; a preface; and a bibliography, Bibliographie), newsletter (Désiré, l'Ami de la Littérature Populaire, includes G. S. article), G. S. notes. (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Charles Darwin. Typed manuscript (a G. S. forward, Le Voyage d'un Naturaliste autour du Monde De C. Darwin: Avant-Propos). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Alphonse Daudet. Typed manuscript. (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Léon Daudet. Press clipping (pasted onto the reverse of a sheet of paper with Vichy-era letterhead for "L'Unité Française", "L'Université Jeune de France", and Gilbert Sigaux as the "Délégué général pour l'Afrique du Nord".). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Marcia Davenport. Press clipping. (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Debray (Pierre Debray / Quentin Ritzen). Typed manuscripts (G. S. articles: 2 drafts of l'Odeur du Temps, and Tchekhov par Quentin Ritzen), press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Jacques Debû-Bridel. Press clipping. (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Jacques Decrest. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Maurice Dekobra. Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Maurice Dekobra), 2 pamphlets promoting M. Dekobra's work (includes G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Lucien Descaves. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Marie Anne Desmarest. Press clippings (including a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Pierre Devaux. Press clippings. (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Monica Dickens. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. forward, Monica Dickens, Avant-Propos). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Diderot. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. prefaces: 2 drafts of one preface, and a single draft of another). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Roland Dorgelès. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- John dos Passos. Press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Maurice Druon. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Charles Du Bos. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Jean Duché. Typed manuscript (article, Jean Duché). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Georges Duhamel. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles/prefaces: 2 drafts of Georges Duhamel, and 3 drafts of Confession de Minuit). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Raymond Dumay. Press clippings (G. S. articles, 2 are pasted on paper with "Unité Française", Vichy-era letterhead) (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Duranty {Michel Crouzet} (Louis Edmond Duranty). Press clipping, typed manuscript (G. S. review of Michel Crouzet's Un méconnu du réalisme: Duranty, 1833-1880). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Jean du Vignaud. Press clipping (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Livres de France). (Box 62, Folder 2)
- l'Ecole des Biches, Lattès 1981. Typed and handwritten manuscript (2 drafts of a G. S. preface). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Ilya Ehrenbourg. Typed manuscript (photocopy of a G. S. preface, Les Aventures Extraordinaires de Julio Jurenito, Préface). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- T. S. Eliot. Press clippings (includes a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Luc Estang. Press clippings, handwritten manuscript (G. S. article, Luc Estang: Romancier, poète, et essayiste), G. S. notes, typed biography and bibliography. (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Edouard Estaunié. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article/preface, La Vie Secrète). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- A. Eustis. Journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- René Fallet. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Léon-Paul Fargue. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles: Léon-Paul Fargue, and Érivains d'aujourd'hui: Léon-Paul Fargue), press clippings. (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Howard Fast. Press clipping (G. S. article), typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, Spartacus Howard Fast, Préface). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Faulkner (William Falkner). Press clippings (G. S. articles), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, William Faulkner). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Elie Faure. Empty folder. (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Edna Ferber. Typed manuscript (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, La Ruée vers l'Ouest). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Ramon Fernandez. Press clippings (2 copies of G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Léo-Ferré. Manuscrit, Essai écrit en juillet 1962. G. S. notes, handwritten and typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. publication/essay: Gilbert Sigaux. Léo Ferré. Éditions de l'Heure, 1962. Includes a discography). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Pierre Fisson. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Pierre Fisson: Romancier). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Max-Pol Fouchet. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Max-Pol Fouchet: Poète et essayiste). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Anatole France. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Nino Frank. Journal excerpts (4 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Gustav Frenssen. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Stéphane Frontès. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Jeanne Galzy. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Théophile Gautier. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. book review, and 3 drafts of a G. S. preface). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Maurice Genevoix. Typed manuscript (a G. S. article, Raboliot, Prix Goncourt 1925). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- André Gide. Press clippings (G. S. articles), typed manuscript (G. S. preface). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Elena Gill. Press clippings, program for an exposition of Elena Gill sculptures and Robert Defago paintings (includes G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Ernst Glaeser. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Gobineau (Joseph Arthur, Comte de Gobineau). Typed manuscript (article, Gobineau 1816-1882). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Goethe (Johann Wolfgang von Goethe). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles: Goethe: Faust, and Notre Faust), press clippings (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Gogol (Nicolas Gogol). Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. forward, and one draft of a G. S. preface Classiques Russes - Tome 26: Préface - Les Veillées du Hameau). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Oliver Goldsmith. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Witold Gombrowicz. Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Witold Gobrowicz), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Gontcharov (Ivan Alexandrovitch Gontcharov). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. preface, Préface à Oblomov). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Henri Gouhier. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Julien Gracq. Journal excerpts (includes a G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Julien Gracq (pseudonyme de Louis Poirier): Romancier). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Julien Green. Press clipping (G. S. article), journal excerpts (includes G. S. articles), periodicals (2 copies of the same l'Avant Scène), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article), a small card from L'Avant Scène (inscribed: "De la pars de Léonard Keigel et avec nos Compliments"). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Graham Greene. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), press clippings (G. S. articles), typed manuscript (Greene). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Robert Greenwood. Press clipping. (Box 62, Folder 4)